It's like this big box. This is what it looks like. And so this is between me and the whales, and at times that feels like a block between you and reality. Is there a difference when it's just your phone? Last year, I went to Uluru in Central Australia, which is this massive rock that towers over the desert. This is sacred land to Anangu, who are the Aboriginal people from this area and the traditional owners of the land. There are particular spots in Uluru that you cannot photograph professionally, because they are culturally sensitive, equivalent to sacred scripture to Anangu. So because of this, most of my photographs are from either far away, like this one, or from specific angles in the park. You could say that some of the most interesting and beautiful visuals in Uluru are located in these sensitive areas, but the request not to photograph them is an explicit and direct invitation to learn more about the land, its importance and its people. Isn't that what we should be doing anyway? So my visit to Uluru quickly became not about me but about connecting with the place. Ironically and unsurprisingly, I have found that presence and connection also happens to make for more compelling images. We can probably all point to social media as being a good place to share the images from our travels and from our lives. We not only share pieces of the world that we have seen but also parts of our day-to-day experiences. And if we're applying intentionality to the photos we take, then hopefully we're sharing intentionally too. For me, allowing people to see pieces of my story and my perspective online has reminded me that I'm not alone. It's helped me build support and community to do the same for others. Let me be clear: I am not trying to discourage you from taking photos. Even if thousands of people have been to whatever exact location and taken whatever exact photo, I encourage you to get out and create too. The world needs every voice and perspective, and yours is included. But what I'm trying to show you is that the phone or camera doesn't have to stay out all the time. What I'm trying to encourage you to do is to put it away, just for a moment -- a moment for you. So let's go back to Mesa Arch, the way that the rock glows orange and the lovely layers of blue in the background. What if the next time you were somewhere amazing, you couldn't bring your camera or phone? What if you were not allowed to take any pictures at all? Would it feel like a limitation? Or would it feel like a relief? So what can we do? Well, the next time you feel the impulse to take out your camera or phone, or, in my case, once you realize you have already pulled it out -- (Laughter) First: stop. Pause. Take a deep breath. Look around. What do you notice? Are you experiencing this moment with someone else? Remember that this moment only comes once. Photography can be part of a beautiful experience. Just don't let it be a block between you and reality. Be intentional, and don't lose a beautiful, irreplaceable memory, because you were too focused on getting the shot. Thank you. (Applause)
Es como una gran caja. Esto es a lo que se parece. Y esto es entre yo y las ballenas, y a veces eso se siente como un muro entre tú y la realidad. ¿Hay alguna diferencia cuando es su teléfono? El año pasado, fui a Uluru en el centro de Australia, que es esta roca masiva que se eleva sobre el desierto. Esta es la tierra sagrada para los anagu, los aborígenes de este área, y los propietarios tradicionales de esta tierra. Hay lugares particulares en Uluru que no puede fotografiar profesionalmente porque son culturalmente sensibles, equivalentes a las sagradas escrituras para los anangu. Debido a esto, la mayoría de mis fotos son desde muy lejos, como esta, o desde ángulos específicos en el parque. Se podría decir que algunas de las imágenes más interesantes y bellas en Uluru están localizadas en estas áreas sensibles, pero la petición de no fotografiarlos es una invitación explícita y directa para aprender más sobre la tierra, su importancia y su gente. ¿No es lo que deberíamos estar haciendo? Así que mi visita a Uluru rápidamente no era sobre mí sino sobre conectar con el lugar. Irónicamente y como era de esperar, he encontrado esa presencia y conexión también resulta en crear imágenes más atractivas. Probablemente todos podemos señalar a las redes sociales como un buen lugar para compartir imágenes de nuestros viajes y vidas. No solo podemos compartir partes del mundo que hemos visto sino también partes de nuestras experiencias diarias. Y si estamos aplicando intencionalidad a las fotos que tomamos, entonces esperamos compartirlas también intencionalmente. Para mí, permitir que la gente vea partes de mi historia y perspectiva online me recuerda que no estoy sola. Me ayudó a construir apoyo y comunidad para hacer lo mismo por otros. Permítame clarificarlo: no estoy tratando de desanimarlos para que no tomen fotos. Incluso si miles de personas han estado en cualquier ubicación exacta y han tomado cualquier foto exacta, les animo a salir y crear también. El mundo necesita cada voz y perspectiva, y las suyas incluidas. Pero lo que intento mostrarle es que el teléfono o cámara no tienen que estar fuera todo el tiempo. Lo que trato de alentarles a hacer es guardarlos, solo por un momento, un momento para Uds. Así que volvamos a Mesa Arch, la forma en que la roca brilla naranja y las hermosas capas de azul en el fondo. ¿Y si la próxima vez que estuvieran en un lugar increíble no pudieran llevar su cámara o su teléfono? ¿Qué pasaría si no le permitieran tomar ninguna fotografía? ¿Se sentiría como una limitación? ¿O se sentiría como un alivio? ¿Qué podemos hacer? Bueno, la próxima vez que sientan el impulso de sacar su cámara o teléfono o, en mi caso, una vez que se hayan dado cuenta de que ya la sacaron... (Risas) Primero, paren. Pausa. Tómense un respiro. Miren alrededor. ¿Qué perciben? ¿Están experimentando este momento con otra persona? Recuerden que este momento solo llega una vez. La fotografía puede ser parte de una bella experiencia. No dejen que sea un muro entre Uds. y la realidad. Vean el sentido y no pierdan un recuerdo bello, irremplazable, por estar muy concentrados en conseguir la fotografía. Gracias. (Aplausos)